Shannon Kotraba

803-417-9454 skotraba@gmail.com Raleigh, NC 27613

https://github.com/skotraba https://www.linkedin.com/in/shannon-kotraba-346290126/ https://skotraba.github.io/

Summary:

Junior Software Developer and former U.S. Army Medic. I have taken some time off after graduating to dedicate myself to improving my programming skills even further. I have had a mentor with a computer science degree guide me. Experienced with Object-Oriented Programming, and Front-End Development. Strong willingness to learn and master Full-Stack Development.

Coding Skills:

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, and C++
- Exposure to C#, SQL and PHP
- Understanding of Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- Linux
- Versions Control Systems
- Proficient with Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Photoshop

Soft Skills:

- Ambitious with a strong desire to learn
- Ability to understand and express technical information clearly, both orally and in writing, when reporting results and explaining procedures to others
- Problem solving, patience and attention to detail while working
- Comfortable with working with large amounts of data
- Ability to understand and solve simple to complex theoretical problems
- Ability to perform advanced mathematics and statistical analysis

Personal Projects:

- Color Picker
 - A window that shows a color wheel and allows the user to select a color. Based on the user selection, two other colors are generated to show a triadic color scheme. A useful program for artist and designers. The values were calculated using properties of an equilateral triangle. Written in C++ using the SFML library for graphics.
- Spanish Learning
 - Spanish learning is a website source provider for learning the Spanish language. This is a personal project that I created because I love learning Spanish in my free time. I designed a theme centered around learning and provided some of my favorite learning resources. I created a JavaScript flashcard program for the user to test themselves on some basic Spanish questions. Link is available on my portfolio.
- Recipe Calculator
 - A console command program that takes user inputted information about ingredients and stores them in a recipe. The
 user can view the recipes and have the program calculate calories per servings or calories based on the weight of a
 given serving. Written in Python.

Experience:

- Internship as Analytical Chemical Technician at Pneuma Respiratory Fall 2019 September-December
 - Worked on a team to conduct and analyze experiments using standard analytical laboratory equipment. Organized data to be in a presentable format.
- Four years in the Army as a Healthcare Specialist 68W 2012-2016
 - Nine Months in Egypt providing first response security 2014
 - Worked as a team and individually to provide front gate security and tower security
 - One-year Medical Clinical Experience 2015-2016
 - Worked under the supervision of a physician to provide patient care and organize and ensure appointments were done efficiently
- Student Veteran Receptionist at Appalachian State University 2018

Education:

- Bachelor's in Chemistry, Minor in Criminal Justice Appalachian State University (2016-2019)
 - o Related Coursework: Analytical Physics I & II, Calculus with Analytical Geometry I & II, Introduction to Statistics
- 68W Medical Training San Antonio, TX EMT (2013-2017)